Aaron Niskin

3415 Chase Ave — Miami Beach, FL 33140 **☎** (305) 894-6475 • ⋈ aaron@niskin.org • 🖆 aaron.niskin.org

HR Department October 3, 2016

Blackrock 40 East 52nd Street 10022 New York, NY

Dear Sir or Madam,

I am a first year graduate student in the Data Science program at the New College of Florida. I would like to spend my 2017 summer learning and Internship with the Analyst Program at BlackRock. As a Mathematician entering the field of statistical computing and Machine Learning, there is no better place to be than Blackrock I believe I have the educational background, academic achievement, and passion to be an outstanding member of your team.

I have previously worked full time as a content developer at XYZ. I was in the Quant team at XYZ where I got to hone my quantitative and analytical skills. As a part of my job I had to constantly communicate with the publishing and marketing team of the company which improved my communication and team leadership skills. In addition, at the University XYZ, I currently taking various courses in Fixed Income, Statistical Modelling, and Portfolio Management where I am learning various financial models and quantitative methods used in the finance industry. I believe that the theoretical and practical knowledge I gained from my graduate program along with my passion to learn new things, will enable me to significantly contribute to your company.

I hope that you will find me well qualified for the Summer Intern Position and I would like to reiterate my strong interest to discuss this opportunity and my qualifications with you further.

Thank you very much for your time and consideration.

Sincerely yours,

Aaron Niskin

Attached: curriculum vitæ

Aaron Niskin

3415 Chase Ave - Miami Beach, FL 33140 **☎** (305) 894-6475 • ⋈ aaron@niskin.org • ⋈ aaron.niskin.org

Skills and Languages

Advanced: JAVASCRIPT, HTML, PYTHON*, R* | Spanish

Intermediate: Clojure, Scheme, Hoplon, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, NodeJS | Hebrew

Basic: JAVA, HASKELL, MONGODB, LATEX, MATLAB, OCTAVE | German

*Projected - based on current workload

Education

New College of Florida Sarasota Master's In Data Science 2016-(2018)

Florida International University

Miami

Bachelor of Science | Mathematics Minors | Physics and English 2012-2015

- Graduated Cum Laude GPA 3.64 (3.79 in major)
- Dean's List (6 times)

Miami Dade College Miami 2010-2011 Associate of Arts

- Graduated with Honors GPA 3.74 out of 4.00
- Dean's List (5 times)
- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society Member
- Physics Award

Experience

Miami

Florida Vocation Institute Computer Science Instructor 2015-2016

- Taught and created syllabi for courses in HTML, CSS, CSS-Frameworks, JavaScript, SQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Functional-Programming, and Basic-Logic
- Created a free online course intended to teach aspiring students about the above subjects through interesting projects (currently live at www.fvi-grad.com)

Math-Busters (www.Math-Busters.com)

Miami

Co-founder and Math/Science/Computing Tutor

2010-2015

- Co-founded a successful income generating tutoring company (www.Math-Busters.com)
- Tutored all levels of students from Elementary School to upper-level University students

Infantryman

1st Battalion of the 38th Infantry Regiment, 2nd ID, US Army

Fort Lewis. WA

2006-2009

- Deployed to Iraq from 2007-2008
- Held positions as a Rifleman, M-240B assistant gunner, M-249 SAW gunner, Radio Telephone Operator, Grenadier, Designated Marksman, and a Team Leader.
- Combat Lifesaver certification
- Assisted in fighting the Tripod Complex forest fire in Winthrop, Washington.

478th Civilian Affairs Battalion, US Army

Perrine. FL

Civil Affairs Specialist

2004-2006

- Trained at the John F. Kennedy Special Warfare Center and School in Fort Bragg, NC for 6 months.Obtained Secret Clearance